const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What type of glands are sweat glands?","answers":[{"option":"Merocrine glands","bool":true},{"option":"Branched acinar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Holocrine glands","bool":false},{"option":"Seromucous glands","bool":false},{"option":"Mammary glands","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What does vitamin C deficiency lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Blood clotting disorders","bool":false},{"option":"Night blindness","bool":false},{"option":"Rickets","bool":false},{"option":"Beri beri","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen disorders","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"When a cell undergoes injury, certain mechanisms cause the activation of proapoptotic bodies in the cell. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this activation?","answers":[{"option":"Mitochondrial damage","bool":false},{"option":"Ca⁺² entry into cell","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased ATP synthesis","bool":false},{"option":"Production of free radicals","bool":false},{"option":"DNA damage","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which type of gland has branched ducts?","answers":[{"option":"Endocrine","bool":false},{"option":"Simple","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial glands","bool":false},{"option":"Compound","bool":true},{"option":"Sweat glands","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which cells are responsible for the production of testosterone?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior pituitary cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus cells","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"A 14-year-old female presents to the clinic with a depressed nasal bridge, short stature, and prominent crease on the palm. The doctor suspects Down syndrome. What is the disease otherwise known as?","answers":[{"option":"Trisomy 16","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 13","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 23","bool":false},{"option":"Trisomy 21","bool":true},{"option":"Trisomy 18","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"During translation, the initiation codon of mRNA attaches to the ribosome at which site?","answers":[{"option":"E site of 50S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"E site of 30S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"A site of 30S subunit","bool":false},{"option":"P site of 30S subunit","bool":true},{"option":"A site of 50S subunit","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the coupled transport of two different molecules in opposite directions called?","answers":[{"option":"Biport","bool":false},{"option":"Uniport","bool":false},{"option":"Cotransport","bool":false},{"option":"Symport","bool":false},{"option":"Antiport","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding amniocentesis?","answers":[{"option":"It can be performed transabdominally and by trans-cervical methods","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal cells are obtained to examine their DNA","bool":false},{"option":"It is guided by ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"It is performed after 22 weeks of gestation","bool":true},{"option":"20-30 ml of fluid is extracted","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"When is chorionic villus sampling performed?","answers":[{"option":"10-12  weeks","bool":true},{"option":"16-18 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"12-14 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"13-15 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"18-22 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following conditions is not an indication for prenatal diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Previous baby born with a birth defect","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal age greater than 15 years","bool":true},{"option":"Repeated history of viral infections","bool":false},{"option":"Previous spontaneous miscarriages in 1st trimester","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal age greater than 35 years","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Extracellular fluid constitutes how much of the total body fluid?","answers":[{"option":"1/6th","bool":false},{"option":"1/12th","bool":false},{"option":"1/4th","bool":false},{"option":"1/8th","bool":false},{"option":"1/3rd","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following is defined as the outcome of the man-made part of the environment?","answers":[{"option":"Laws","bool":false},{"option":"Society","bool":false},{"option":"Green houses","bool":false},{"option":"Tradition","bool":false},{"option":"Culture","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What are the inclusion bodies formed in plasma cells due to excessive production of immunoglobulin called?","answers":[{"option":"Lipofuscin","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot-Leyden crystals","bool":false},{"option":"Russell bodies","bool":true},{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false},{"option":"Kulchitsky cells","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What are the phospholipid masses that replace cells that have undergone necrosis called?","answers":[{"option":"Myelin figures","bool":true},{"option":"Lipofuscin","bool":false},{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false},{"option":"Russell bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Charcot-Leyden crystals","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following hormones influence the process of sperm formation?","answers":[{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"LH and testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"LH","bool":false},{"option":"FSH","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following is used for the diagnosis of Klinefelter syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false},{"option":"Percutaneous umbilical blood sampling","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"DNA karyotyping","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"In which of the following conditions does isosmotic volume contraction occur?","answers":[{"option":"Increased antidiuretic hormone (ADH) secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"Increased absorption of salts from intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive blood loss","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following is the base sequence for a start codon?","answers":[{"option":"UAA","bool":false},{"option":"AGU","bool":false},{"option":"UGA","bool":false},{"option":"UAG","bool":false},{"option":"AUG","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following is present at the 3' end of a tRNA?","answers":[{"option":"CCA","bool":true},{"option":"GGT","bool":false},{"option":"AUG","bool":false},{"option":"UAG","bool":false},{"option":"UAA","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which drug prevents the synthesis of folic acid?","answers":[{"option":"Probenecid","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Chloramphenicol","bool":false},{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"In prokaryotes, initiation of the transcription involves recognition of the initial site by which factor of RNA polymerase enzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha factor","bool":false},{"option":"Enzyme assembly factor","bool":false},{"option":"Beta factor","bool":false},{"option":"Sigma factor","bool":true},{"option":"Template binding factor","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Ribosomes are found attached to which of the following organelles?","answers":[{"option":"Mitochondria","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false},{"option":"Vacuole","bool":false},{"option":"Rough endoplasmic reticulum","bool":true},{"option":"Golgi apparatus","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Quinolones inhibit the activity of which of the following enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"RNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"RNA primer","bool":false},{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase 2","bool":true},{"option":"DNA polymerase","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the average size of a bacterial cell?","answers":[{"option":"0.2-5 μm","bool":true},{"option":"5-10 μm","bool":false},{"option":"0.03-0.05 μm","bool":false},{"option":"50-80 μm","bool":false},{"option":"10-15 μm","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following distinguishes prokaryotic and eukaryotic cells?","answers":[{"option":"Shape of cell","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of multiple nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of ribosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Presence of membrane bound organelles","bool":true},{"option":"Presence of vacuoles","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"DNA polymerase 1 is able to remove an RNA primer due to which activity?","answers":[{"option":"3'-5' unwinding","bool":false},{"option":"5'-3' unwinding","bool":false},{"option":"3'-5' exonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"5'-3' polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"5'-3' exonuclease","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding LDL?","answers":[{"option":"Prevents heart attack","bool":false},{"option":"Contains high concentration of cholesterol","bool":true},{"option":"Stands for \"light density lactoproteins\"","bool":false},{"option":"Contains low concentration of cholesterol","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents liver disease","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"By which mechanism do bacteria reproduce?","answers":[{"option":"Mating","bool":false},{"option":"Conjugation","bool":false},{"option":"Mitosis","bool":false},{"option":"Binary fission","bool":true},{"option":"Meiosis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the amount of amniotic fluid aspirated during an amniocentesis?","answers":[{"option":"20-30 mL","bool":true},{"option":"7-8 mL","bool":false},{"option":"5-10 mL","bool":false},{"option":"40-50 mL","bool":false},{"option":"10-12 mL","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following produces negative supercoils in the DNA strand?","answers":[{"option":"Ligase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase 1","bool":false},{"option":"Gyrase","bool":true},{"option":"Transcriptase","bool":false},{"option":"Helicase","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following types of bacteria is found in swimming pools?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Leptospira","bool":true},{"option":"Candida","bool":false},{"option":"Helicobacter","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Rocky Mountain spotted fever is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Spirochaetes","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium","bool":false},{"option":"Rickettsia","bool":true},{"option":"Salmonella","bool":false},{"option":"Coxiella","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of these is the longest phase of the cell cycle?","answers":[{"option":"G2","bool":false},{"option":"G1","bool":true},{"option":"Prophase","bool":false},{"option":"M","bool":false},{"option":"S","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which one of the following is not a gram-negative bacterium?","answers":[{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Campylobacter jejuni","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What fraction of body fluid is the plasma?","answers":[{"option":"1/12 of total body fluid","bool":true},{"option":"1/2 of total body fluid","bool":false},{"option":"2/3 of total body fluid","bool":false},{"option":"1/10 of total body fluid","bool":false},{"option":"1/4 of total body fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which type of RNA is involved in splicing?","answers":[{"option":"snRNA","bool":true},{"option":"rRNA","bool":false},{"option":"mRNA","bool":false},{"option":"tRNA","bool":false},{"option":"dsRNA","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"In xeroderma pigmentosum, there is accumulation of which substance due to ultraviolet light exposure?","answers":[{"option":"Cytosine dimers","bool":false},{"option":"Guanine dimers","bool":false},{"option":"Cysteine dimers","bool":false},{"option":"Adenine dimers","bool":false},{"option":"Thymine dimers","bool":true}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following statements is false?","answers":[{"option":"Endotoxins are present in gram-positive bacteria","bool":true},{"option":"Exotoxins are produced by both gram-positive and gram-negative bacteria","bool":false},{"option":"Endotoxin are heat-stable lipopolysaccharide-protein complex","bool":false},{"option":"Exotoxins may be heat-stabile proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Endotoxins are present in gram-negative bacteria","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is ethnocentrism?","answers":[{"option":"Belief that video games are actually good for you","bool":false},{"option":"Placing a speaker system in the middle of the room","bool":false},{"option":"Belief of superiority of one's personal ethnic group","bool":true},{"option":"Belief of superiority of one's religion","bool":false},{"option":"Belief that you are the best despite having no way to prove it","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What does vomiting lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Where was the first Middle Eastern Regional conference held?","answers":[{"option":"Jordan","bool":true},{"option":"London","bool":false},{"option":"Karachi","bool":false},{"option":"Las vegas","bool":false},{"option":"Geneva","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of these is a fat-soluble vitamin?","answers":[{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecalciferol","bool":true},{"option":"Biocidin","bool":false},{"option":"Biotin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What regulates homeostasis?","answers":[{"option":"Brain (pons) and exocrine system","bool":false},{"option":"Mammary glands and sweat glands","bool":false},{"option":"Brain (hypothalamus) and endocrine system","bool":true},{"option":"Brain (pons) and hands","bool":false},{"option":"Exocrine and endocrine system","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the effect of drugs on the body called?","answers":[{"option":"Pharmacogenesis","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacogenomics","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacodynamics","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacokinetics","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the karyotype in Klinefelter's syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"45 XO","bool":false},{"option":"47 XXY","bool":true},{"option":"45 OO","bool":false},{"option":"47 XXX","bool":false},{"option":"46 XY","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the karyotype in Turner's syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"47 XXX","bool":false},{"option":"45 XO","bool":true},{"option":"45 OO","bool":false},{"option":"46 XY","bool":false},{"option":"47 XXY","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which type of necrosis occurs in the walls of the arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Coagulative","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive","bool":false},{"option":"Gangrenous","bool":false},{"option":"Caseous","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinoid","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What important structural feature does the Golgi type 1 neuron possess?","answers":[{"option":"Single long dendron","bool":false},{"option":"Short axon","bool":false},{"option":"No axon","bool":false},{"option":"Multiple axons","bool":false},{"option":"Single long axon","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Why does edema occur?","answers":[{"option":"Thickened endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased capillary pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Fever","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased water consumption","bool":false},{"option":"Increased capillary pressure","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following do the typical spinal nerves not supply?","answers":[{"option":"Arrector pili muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary muscles of the eyes","bool":true},{"option":"Skeletal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Sweat glands","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What model does a holistic doctor use?","answers":[{"option":"Biopsychosocial model","bool":true},{"option":"Planned model","bool":false},{"option":"Instagram model","bool":false},{"option":"Online model","bool":false},{"option":"Holy model","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the ability of the drug to elicit a response after binding to a receptor called?","answers":[{"option":"Elimination","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic activity","bool":true},{"option":"Efficacy","bool":false},{"option":"Potency","bool":false},{"option":"Pharmacology","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"In which phase are the primary oocytes in females arrested?","answers":[{"option":"Prophase 1 of meiosis","bool":true},{"option":"Prophase of mitosis","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphase 1 of meiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Prophase 2 of meiosis","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which cell of the connective tissue secretes fibers and ground substance?","answers":[{"option":"Osteocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Fibroblasts","bool":true},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the ability to distinguish two closely related points known as?","answers":[{"option":"Focal length","bool":false},{"option":"Magnification","bool":false},{"option":"Power","bool":false},{"option":"Resolving power","bool":true},{"option":"Navigation","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which type of epithelium is generally present for the protection of the underlying tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudostratified epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified non-keratinized squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified keratinized squamous epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Stratified cuboidal epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which type of protein anchors the cell to extracellular fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Insoluble protein","bool":false},{"option":"Globular protein","bool":false},{"option":"Integrins","bool":true},{"option":"Antibody","bool":false},{"option":"Lipoprotein","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is a set of DNA coming in pairs, one from each parent, called?","answers":[{"option":"Chromosome","bool":true},{"option":"Mutation","bool":false},{"option":"Phenotype","bool":false},{"option":"Gene","bool":false},{"option":"Chromatid","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Chromosomes are best studied in which phase of the cell cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Prophase","bool":false},{"option":"Anaphase","bool":false},{"option":"Telophase","bool":false},{"option":"Metaphase","bool":true},{"option":"G1","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"At room temperature, unsaturated triglycerides are found in which form?","answers":[{"option":"Gas","bool":false},{"option":"Wax","bool":false},{"option":"Volatile liquid","bool":false},{"option":"Solid","bool":false},{"option":"Liquid","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Triglycerides are hydrolyzed by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Lipase","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrate","bool":false},{"option":"Catalase","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolase","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which statement is false?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus epidermidis is a non-pathogen on skin","bool":false},{"option":"Group B streptococci is present in normal flora of vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal bacteria help in synthesis and absorption of several minerals","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus mutans can be commonly found in dental plaques","bool":false},{"option":"Yeast is not part of the normal flora","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of these is true regarding bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Their DNA is surrounded by a nuclear membrane","bool":false},{"option":"They are genetically haploid","bool":true},{"option":"Their method of replication is budding","bool":false},{"option":"They have linear DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Gram-negative bacterial cell membranes are rich in teichoic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Necrosis is usually termed as \"accidental cell death\" and has a number of types based on distinctive gross appearances. Which of the following is the type of necrosis that can only be detected upon histological examination?","answers":[{"option":"Fat necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Gangrenous necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinoid necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Caseous necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive necrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What are the main cations and anions of the extracellular fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Potassium and chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium and phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium and chloride","bool":true},{"option":"Potassium and bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium and bicarbonate","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What is the concentration of Na⁺ in the extracellular fluid?","answers":[{"option":"14 mmol/L","bool":false},{"option":"14 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"142 mEq/L","bool":true},{"option":"1.42 mEq/L","bool":false},{"option":"18.9 mmol/L","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"The total water content of the body is best given by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"60-70%","bool":true},{"option":"10-20%","bool":false},{"option":"30-40%","bool":false},{"option":"50-60%","bool":false},{"option":"70-80%","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"During the metaphase stage of mitosis, how are chromosomes observed?","answers":[{"option":"Lined up at equatorial plate","bool":true},{"option":"Condensed chromosomes randomly distributed","bool":false},{"option":"Recombined in mitosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulled apart to opposite poles","bool":false},{"option":"Not seen as they are yet to condense","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following terms describes the anatomical rotation of atlantoaxial joint?","answers":[{"option":"Biaxial","bool":false},{"option":"Triaxial","bool":false},{"option":"Multiaxial","bool":false},{"option":"Uniaxial","bool":true},{"option":"Does not involve any axis","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"The properties of surface tension, high viscosity, and vaporization in water are caused by which of the following molecular interactions?","answers":[{"option":"Dipole movements","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen bonds","bool":true},{"option":"Van der Waal forces","bool":false},{"option":"Sulfahydryl bonds","bool":false},{"option":"Covalent bonds","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Triglycerides are formed by which of the following molecules?","answers":[{"option":"Adenosine and phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acids","bool":false},{"option":"Deoxyribose and nitrogenous base","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acid and lectin","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acid and alcohol","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What can cause pyrimidine dimers in DNA?","answers":[{"option":"Infrared light","bool":false},{"option":"Ultraviolet light","bool":true},{"option":"Radio waves","bool":false},{"option":"Inherited disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Missense mutation","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which fluid is sampled during an amniocentesis?","answers":[{"option":"Maternal blood","bool":false},{"option":"Amniotic fluid","bool":true},{"option":"Fetal blood","bool":false},{"option":"Chorionic villi","bool":false},{"option":"Amniotic cells interstitial fluid","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"In which condition is amniocentesis usually performed?","answers":[{"option":"Alcoholic mother","bool":false},{"option":"Blood spotting during pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal age of 35 or more","bool":true},{"option":"Teenage pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Family history of ovarian cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which structure in a gram-positive bacteria is concerned with septic shock?","answers":[{"option":"Peptidoglycan wall","bool":false},{"option":"Pilus","bool":false},{"option":"Flagellum","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Teichoic acid","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which structure of a bacteria is concerned with the quellung reactions?","answers":[{"option":"Flagellum","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Cytoplasmic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Peptidoglycans","bool":false},{"option":"Pilus","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which bacterial structure helps in chemotaxis towards nutrients?","answers":[{"option":"Teichoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Flagella","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Pili","bool":false},{"option":"Plasmid","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which structure helps in the attachment of bacteria to surfaces?","answers":[{"option":"Pilus","bool":true},{"option":"Teichoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Flagella","bool":false},{"option":"Cytoplasmic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"What could be a possible step in the confirmation of the diagnosis of Down's syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"Genealogical DNA test","bool":false},{"option":"Computerized tomography (CT) scan","bool":false},{"option":"DNA karyotyping","bool":true},{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"A 5-year-old boy is brought to a clinic of a tertiary care hospital with his parents complaining that he has not yet started walking unsupported nor has he started speaking. He appears short for his age and is plump. He also has a depressed nasal bridge and small ears. He looks very different from his siblings and is a very slow learner. He is unable to feed himself and is not toilet-trained yet. He was born about 10 years later than his brother when his mother’s age was 45 years. All other family members are normal. He has a small head, and his tongue appears larger because it appeared to be protruding out of the mouth all the time. His hands are small with the fifth finger bent towards the fourth and there is only a single palmar crease. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Patau syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Niemann-Pick disease","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2016","question":"Which of the following is measured in the maternal serum for prenatal diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"AFP, hCG, and estriol","bool":true},{"option":"hCG and AFP","bool":false},{"option":"Estriol and progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"AFP","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin, hCG, and AFP","bool":false}]}]
export default arr